Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Burt Manning Papers, 1956-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Burt Manning papers 1956-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
27.0 linear feet Extent: 14,000 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Burt Manning was an advertising executive at JWT who served as Chief Creative Officer and Chairman/Chief Executive Officer (1987-1998). Collection spans the years 1956-1988 and includes correspondence, reports, policy manuals, presentations, speeches and other materials that document Manning's career as Creative Director and executive at JWT offices in Chicago and New York. Companies represented include American Advertising Federation, American Association of Advertising Agencies, Association of National Advertisers, Burger King, Ford, GTE Sprint, Institute of Life Insurance, Leo Burnett, Miller, Pepsi, Quaker Oats (Aunt Jemima, Ken-L-Ration, Puss 'n Boots), Schlitz, Scott Paper, Twentieth Century Fox and the U.S. Marine Corps. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00726
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Research Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Burt Manning Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1931 May 31 Burton Manning born
1949-1950 Attended the University of Illinois
1955 Copy writer, Wieboldt Department Store
1956 Brook Smith French & Dorrance (Detroit)
1958 Leo Burnett
1966 Associate Creative Director, Leo Burnett; Later in year hired as Copy Supervisor, JWT Chicago. Credited with slogan for Schlitz: When You're Out of Schlitz, You're Out of Beer
1970 Senior Vice President, Co-Creative Director, JWT Chicago
1972 Transferred to JWT New York
1974 Creative Director, JWT New York; elected to Management Committee
1977 Executive Vice President, Executive Creative Director, JWT New York; named Vice Chairman of JWT
1980 Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, JWT USA
1986 Resigned from JWT USA to become Partner and Chairman of the Executive Committee, Jordan Case Taylor & McGrath (renamed Jordan Manning Case Taylor & McGrath
1987 Returned to JWT as Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
1989 Named AdWeek Executive of the Year
1995 Chairman, American Association of Advertising Agencies; and Director of the Advertising Council
1995 Elected to National Sales and Marketing Hall of Fame
1998 Retired from JWT; named Chairman Emeritus; elected to Advertising Hall of Fame
In addition, Burt Manning has served as a trustee for the New School for Social Research; Neuroscience Research Foundation; and the Museum of Television and Radio. He is past Director of the Advertising Education Foundation; the National Actors Theatre; Bob Hope Institute for Heart Research; the National Council for Depressive Illness; and the American Shakespeare Theater. He was a member of the Madison Council Chamber of Commerce. Manning holds an Honorary Doctorate in Fine Arts from the Pratt Institute.
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1956-1988 and includes correspondence, reports, policy manuals, presentations, speeches and other materials that document Manning's career as Creative Director and executive at JWT offices in Chicago and New York. Companies represented include American Advertising Federation, American Association of Advertising Agencies, Association of National Advertisers, Burger King, Ford, GTE Sprint, Institute of Life Insurance, Leo Burnett, Miller, Pepsi, Quaker Oats (Aunt Jemima, Ken-L-Ration, Puss 'n Boots), Schlitz, Scott Paper, Twentieth Century Fox and the U.S. Marine Corps.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged into six series: Account Files; Administrative Files; New Business Files; Writings and Speeches; Audiovisual Materials; and Oversize Materials.
Subject Headings
Manning, Burt; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; American Advertising Federation; American Association of Advertising Agencies; Association of National Advertisers; Burger King Corporation; Ford Motor Company; Institute of Life Insurance; Jos. Schlitz Brewing Co.; Leo Burnett Company; Miller Brewing Company; Pepsi-Cola Company; Quaker Oats Company; Scott Paper Company; Sprint Corp; Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation; United States. Marine Corps; Advertising; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related materials may be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company collections held in the Hartman Center:
Account Files
Domestic Advertisements
International Offices
New Business Records
Detailed Description of Collection
- Account Files, 1971-1987 and undated, (26 boxes)
  - General
    - Client conflicts, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Client presentations, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Client security/confidentiality, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - Multinational accounts report, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Top-20 client lists, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - Various accounts summaries, etc., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Activision, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Allegheny Airline, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - American Greetings, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - American Red Cross, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Bali (blinds), 1985 (Box 1)
  - Baskin-Robbins, 1984-1986 (Box 1)
  - Bausch & Lomb, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Beatrice, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Burgenstock, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Burger King
    - General, 1984-1987, (4 folders) (Box 2)
    - 5-Year Strategic Plan, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Advertising needs, undated (Box 2)
    - Advertising to children, 1976-1977, (3 folders) (Box 2)
    - Black franchisees, undated (Box 2)
    - Burger King Club mailing, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Call reports and miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Creative briefing, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Creative Foods, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Creative pitch notes, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Magic, undated (Box 3)
    - Memoranda, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Non-children, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Presentation notes and ideas, 1976 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Report, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Strategy, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Target Plan, 1976 (Box 3)
  - California Cooler, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Castle & Cooke, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  - Chevron, 1984-1987, (4 folders) (Box 4)
  - Christian Dior, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Computerland, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Coors, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Dean Witter, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Dole, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Eckerd Drug, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Emery Worldwide, 1984 (Box 4)
  - European American Bank (Box 5)
    - General, 1974-1977, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Clippings, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Ford
    - General, 1984-1986, (1-4 of 6 folders) (Box 5)
    - General, 1984-1986, (5-6 of 6 folders) (Box 6)
    - Europe, 1983-1986 (Box 6)
    - Jackie Stewart, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Joseph Schulte, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Presentation, undated (Box 6)
    - Refocusing the Spotlight on Ford, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Robert Rewey, 1984-1985 (Box 6)
    - Strategic Factors Affecting Advertising Planning in the Next Five Years, undated (Box 6)
    - Taurus, 1984 (Box 6)
    - The Role of Market Communications in Selling Automobiles, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Worldwide, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Freddie Mac, 1984-1985 (Box 6)
  - Forum for Freedom (Statue of Liberty advertisement), 1986 (Box 7)
  - Goodyear
    - General, 1984-1985, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - International, 1984 (Box 7)
  - GTE Sprint
    - General, 1983-1987, (1-4 of 9 folders) (Box 7)
    - General, 1983-1987, (5-9 of 9 folders) (Box 8)
    - Account review, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Agency review, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Brief, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    - Marketing profile, 1986 (Box 8)
    - Presentation, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Spacenet, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Health & Tennis Corporation, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
  - Hewlett-Packard, 1984 (Box 9)
  - H. J. Heinz, presentation notes, undated (Box 9)
  - Holiday Inns, last month of relationship, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Hyatt, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - IBM, 1985-1986, (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Institute of Life Insurance (Box 10)
    - General, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Planning, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Isacomm/Meeting Channel, 1984 (Box 10)
  - Johnson & Johnson, 1985 (Box 10)
  - Joseph Schlitz Brewing
    - General, 1977-1981, (2 folders) (Box 10)
    - Project U, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Kellogg's, All-Bran, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Kodak, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 11)
  - Kraft
    - General, 1984-1987 (Box 11)
    - Cheese, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Increasing Cheese Consumption, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Kraft/ADA Cheese Project, 1984 (Box 11)
    - Mike Miles, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Lever Brothers, 1974-1986, (3 folders) (Box 11)
  - Lowenbrau
    - General, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
    - Briefing, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Mattel/Fisher-Price, 1984-1986 (Box 12)
  - Miller Brewing
    - General, 1984-1986, (1-7 of 13 folders) (Box 12)
    - General, 1984-1986, (8-13 of 13 folders) (Box 13)
    - Beer Exec's Year in Review, 1984 (Box 13)
    - Burt Reynolds, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Counterattack, undated (Box 13)
    - De la Cruz & Goachet (Puerto Rico), 1986, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Imact American Beer Market Review and Forecast, 1982, 1984, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Miller High Life, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Miller High Life Marketing Review, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Research, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Scripts and proposals, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Summary of Learning to Date, 1984 (Box 15)
    - The Miller Legacy, undated (Box 15)
    - U.S. Beer Market Overview, 1985 (Box 15)
  - National Alliance Against Violence, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Nabisco, 1984-1986 (Box 15)
  - Nestle/Rowntree, 1984-1986 (Box 15)
  - Norfolk Southern, 1985-1986 (Box 15)
  - Northern Telecom, undated (Box 15)
  - Oscar Mayer
    - General, 1983-1985 (Box 15)
    - 25th Anniversary, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Pacific Stereo, 1977-1978 (Box 15)
  - Pan American World Airline
    - Fact Book, undated (Box 15)
    - Overall Advertising Plan, 1978 (Box 15)
    - TWA and other competitors, 1976 (Box 15)
  - Paramount, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Pepsi
    - General, 1983-1986, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Menudo (music group), 1983-1984 (Box 16)
    - Use of :15 Commercial Units, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Philip Morris, 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - Pillsbury, 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - Quaker Oats
    - General, 1978-1986, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Aunt Jemima
      - General, 1973-1975, (1-3 of 4 folders) (Box 16)
      - General, 1973-1975, (4 of 4 folders) (Box 17)
      - Complete Pancake Mix, 1973-1975 (Box 17)
      - Creative, 1973-1974 (Box 17)
      - French Toast, 1974 (Box 17)
      - Frozen Pancake Batter, 1971-1975 (Box 17)
      - Frozen Waffles, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
      - Frozen Waffles/French Toast, 1973-1975 (Box 17)
      - Jumbo Waffles, 1973-1974 (Box 17)
      - Pancake Batter, 1975 (Box 17)
      - Pancake Mix, 1973-1975 (Box 17)
      - Quick Bread, 1976 (Box 17)
      - Thicker Syrup, 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - T-Plan, 1975 (Box 18)
      - Waffles and French Toast creative, 1973 (Box 18)
      - Whole Wheat Pancakes, 1974-1975 (Box 18)
    - Cat food presentation (JWT Toronto), 1973 (Box 18)
    - Compensation, 1976 (Box 18)
    - Creative reviews, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
    - Ken-L-Ration
      - Biskit, 1972-1974 (Box 18)
      - Burger Line, 1972-1975 (Box 18)
      - Burger-n-Egg Flavor, 1973-1974, (3 folders) (Box 18)
      - Burger-n-Egg Flavor scripts, 1973-1974 (Box 19)
      - Burger Time, 1976 (Box 19)
      - Canned dog food, 1973-1974 (Box 19)
      - Cheese-flavored burger, 1973 (Box 19)
      - Chicken flavor, 1973 (Box 19)
      - Creative (Includes theme song), 1973-1976, (4 folders) (Box 19)
      - Diet Ration, 1972-1974 (Box 19)
      - Dog food creative direction, 1973 (Box 19)
      - Government-Inspected campaign, 1973-1974, (5 folders) (Box 20)
      - Liver Flavor, 1975 (Box 20)
      - Maintenance campaign, 1973-1976, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - My Dog, theme song, 1974 (Box 20)
      - Price-Value campaign, 1974 (Box 21)
      - Puppy Food, 1973-1974, (3 folders) (Box 21)
      - Puppy food creative exploration, 1974 (Box 21)
      - Research, 1972-1974 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      - Scripts, 1972-1973 (Box 21)
      - Semi-Moist/Dry, 1974-1975 (Box 21)
      - Special Cuts, 1974 (Box 21)
      - Spots, 1973 (Box 21)
      - Tender Chunks/Big Chew (Project Ed), 1974-1976, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Location of account, 1976 (Box 22)
    - Meat Extender (textured soy protein), 1974 (Box 22)
    - Memoranda, 1973-1974 (Box 22)
    - New products, 1974-1977 (Box 22)
    - Positioning presentation [FRAGILE], 1974 (Box 22)
    - Premium Beef Extender, 1973-1974, (4 folders) (Box 22)
    - Proposal (Canter Achenbaum Heekin), 1976 (Box 22)
    - Puss-n-Boots
      - Creative, circa 1973 (Box 22)
      - Flavour Morsels (JWT Toronto), 1973, (1 of 4 folders) (Box 22)
      - Flavour Morsels (JWT Toronto), 1973-1974, (2-4 of 4 folders) (Box 23)
  - R.T. French, 1985-1986 (Box 23)
  - Reynolds Metals
    - General, 1985 (Box 23)
    - Business Building/New Products, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Rockefeller Center, 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Ryder Truck Rental, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - S.C. Johnson
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 23)
    - Edge Shaving Gel, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Scott Paper
    - General, 1974-1975 (Box 23)
    - Attitude study, 1974 (Box 23)
    - Lady Scott, 1973-1975 (Box 23)
    - Napkins, 1972-1974 (Box 24)
    - Presentation notes and ideas, undated (Box 24)
    - Research, 1973-1974 (Box 24)
    - Scottowels, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Viva napkins, 1975 (Box 24)
    - Windblossoms, 1974 (Box 24)
  - Sears, 1984-1985 (Box 24)
  - Showtime/The Movie Channel
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 24)
    - Presentation, 1986 (Box 24)
    - Situation analysis, 1984 (Box 24)
  - Standard Brands, 1978 (Box 25)
  - STP Corporation
    - General, 1975 (Box 25)
    - Oil Treatment, 1975-1976, (2 folders) (Box 25)
  - Twentieth Century Fox
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 25)
    - Brand promotions, 1985 (Box 25)
    - Cocoon (film) marketing, includes Tom Benedek screenplay, 1984-1985 (Box 25)
    - David Weitzner correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 25)
    - Enemy Mine (film), includes Edward Khmara screenplay, 1984-1985 (Box 26)
    - Historical Overview: Service and Financial Considerations, 1985 (Box 26)
    - Rhinestone/Olympic Film, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Toys R Us, 1982-1984 (Box 26)
  - Union Carbide, 1985 (Box 26)
  - US Air, 1984-1986 (Box 26)
  - U.S. Marine Corps
    - General, undated (Box 26)
    - Review, 1984-1985 (Box 26)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1984 (Box 26)
  - Warner-Lambert
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 26)
    - Presentation, 1984 (Box 26)
- Administrative Files, 1957-1986 and undated, (17 boxes)
  - 1986 in Review, 1986 (Box 27)
  - AAAA (American Association of Advertising Agencies)
    - Adizes Method of Management Seminar, 1985 (Box 27)
    - Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 27)
    - Committee to Improve Advertising, 1984-1986 (Box 27)
    - Committees, 1985-1986 (Box 27)
    - Creative Committee, 1986 (Box 27)
    - Meeting, 1982-1986, (1-4 of 7 folders) (Box 27)
    - Meeting, 1982-1986, (5-7 of 7 folders) (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Salary questionnaire, 1984 (Box 28)
  - AAF (American Advertising Federation)
    - General, 1985 (Box 28)
    - ADDY Awards, 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Acquisitions, 1984-1986 (Box 28)
  - Adams-Russell/Cable Shop, 1981 (Box 28)
  - Advertising Age Agency Report, 1985-1986 (Box 28)
  - Advertising Management Group, 1986 (Box 29)
  - AEF (Advertising Educational Foundation), 1984 (Box 29)
  - Affirmative action, 1986 (Box 29)
  - Agency compensation, 1984 (Box 29)
  - ANA (Association of National Advertisers)
    - General, 1985 (Box 29)
    - Meeting, 1986 (Box 29)
  - Audio, Video and Presentation Services at JWT, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Bess Myerson (celebrity), 1973-1974 (Box 29)
  - Board of Directors, 1978-1986, (1-3 of 9 folders) (Box 29)
  - Board of Directors, 1978-1986, (4-9 of 9 folders) (Box 30)
  - Brand management, 1984 (Box 30)
  - Burton-Campbell/Tucker Wayne (agencies), 1984-1986 (Box 30)
  - BUY (Brand Utility Yardstick) Study, 1980 (Box 31)
  - Carr Communications, 1986 (Box 31)
  - Charles Balestrino, undated (Box 31)
  - Client invitations, Worldwide Operating Committee Reception, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Clippings, 1967-1977, (9 folders) (Box 31)
  - Code name Elizabeth Taylor, 1985 (Box 31)
  - Communications plans, 1975-1977 (Box 31)
  - Compensation policies, 1984-1986 (Box 31)
  - Competitive agencies, 1985-1986, (3 folders) (Box 32)
  - Comptroller Department Monitoring Report, 1986 Feb., (2 folders) (Box 32)
  - Congratulatory letters, 1975 (Box 32)
  - Consumer Behavior Unit, 1985 (Box 32)
  - Consultants, 1984-1986 (Box 32)
  - Corporate contributions, 1984-1986 (Box 32)
  - Creative Assessment Committee, 1980 (Box 33)
  - Creative awards, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 33)
  - Creative Directors' Meeting, 1978 (Box 33)
  - Creative library, 1984-1986 (Box 33)
  - Creative Review Board--Miles, One-A-Day Vitamins, [NO PHOTOCOPYING]1976 (Box 33)
  - Creative Review Job Squad, 1972 (Box 33)
  - Creative Standards Committee, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Dinner/Occasion acceptances and regrets, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 33)
  - Evaluation of new copy submissions, undated (Box 33)
  - Financial, 1985-1986 (Box 33)
  - Flame of Truth Award dinner, 1980 (Box 33)
  - Gallagher Report, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Guide to Job Performance Appraisal Program, undated (Box 33)
  - In-House agency proposal, undated (Box 33)
  - International transfer policy, undated (Box 34)
  - J. Walter advertisements, 1986 (Box 34)
  - J. Walter USA communications preliminary outline, 1984 (Box 34)
  - JWT/Coopers & Lybrand study, 1985 (Box 34)
  - JWT USA
    - 5-Year History Income Statement, 1980-1984, 1985 (Box 34)
    - Administration, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 34)
    - Marketing plan for 1985-1987, undated (Box 34)
  - Keith Reinhard (Needham Harper), 1985 (Box 34)
  - Kobs & Brady (direct marketing agency), 1985-1986 (Box 34)
  - Legal matters, 1984-1986 (Box 34)
  - Leo Burnett
    - Handbook for Star-Reachers, circa 1957 (Box 34)
    - Memoranda, 1960-1966, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 34)
    - Memoranda, 1960-1966, (2 of 2 folders) (Box 35)
    - Trial (Virginia Richmond v. Schlitz), 1971 (Box 35)
  - Life Magazine 50th Anniversary Issue, correspondence, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Management Committee, undated (Box 35)
  - Management Incentive Plan (MIP), 1978 (Box 35)
  - Management succession, 1984-1986, (5 folders) (Box 35)
  - Marketing Counselors, Inc., 1973 (Box 35)
  - Media
    - General, 1985-1986 (Box 35)
    - Case histories, 1984 (Box 35)
    - Minority media, 1985 (Box 35)
    - Spot media--Press statement on Price Waterhouse report, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Memoranda, 1973-1986, (7 folders) (Box 36)
  - Monitoring report, 1985 (Box 36)
  - Multinational, 1984-1986 (Box 36)
  - Notes and miscellaneous, 1971-1979, (2 folders) (Box 37)
  - Offices and Regions
    - Asia/Pacific, 1986 (Box 37)
    - Atlanta, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 37)
    - Caracas, exhibit, 1985 (Box 37)
    - Chicago
      - General, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 37)
      - Internal audit, 1985 (Box 37)
      - Monthly Manager's Assessment, 1985 (Box 37)
      - Project Hero (Lloyd Stein), 1984 (Box 37)
    - Detroit
      - General, 1984-1986 (Box 38)
      - Internal audit, 1985 (Box 38)
      - Monthly Manager's Assessment, 1986 (Box 38)
    - Europe, 1985 (Box 38)
    - JWT West
      - Monthly Manager's Assessment, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 38)
      - Office review, 1985 (Box 38)
    - Latin America, 1985-1986 (Box 38)
    - Los Angeles
      - General, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 38)
      - Internal audit, 1984 (Box 38)
      - Monthly Manager's Assessment, 1986 (Box 38)
    - New York
      - General, 1984-1985 (Box 39)
      - Annual assessment, 1975 (Box 39)
      - Client contact list, 1984 (Box 39)
      - Creative Department, 1977 (Box 39)
      - Legal matters, 1974-1978 (Box 39)
      - Manager's assessment, 1985-1986 (Box 39)
      - Marketing plan, 1972, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 39)
      - Memoranda, 1974-1976 (Box 39)
      - Television production, 1975 (Box 39)
    - San Francisco
      - General, 1984-1986 (Box 39)
      - Internal audit, 1986 (Box 40)
      - Employee Attitude Study--Action Programs, 1986 (Box 40)
      - Financial History 1979-1984, 1985 (Box 40)
      - Monthly Manager's Assessment, 1986 (Box 40)
    - South Africa
      - General, 1985 (Box 40)
      - Business and Communications Plan, 1978 (Box 40)
    - Various offices, manager's assessments, 1977, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 40)
    - Washington
      - General, 1984-1986 (Box 40)
      - Monthly Manager's Assessment, 1986 (Box 40)
      - Planning, 1985-1986 (Box 40)
      - Political Action Committee, 1984 (Box 40)
      - Political contribution policy, 1985 (Box 40)
      - Price Waterhouse representation letter, 1986 (Box 40)
      - Professional development, 1976 (Box 40)
      - Professional Incentive Plan (PIP), 1985-1986 (Box 40)
      - Profile of Bert Metter, 1978 (Box 40)
      - Public relations, 1984-1986 (Box 40)
  - Publications, 1985-1986 (Box 41)
  - Research
    - General, 1984-1986 (Box 41)
    - 15-Second Commercials, 1984 (Box 41)
    - Harris Study of Advertising Agencies, 1984 (Box 41)
    - JWT Employee Attitude Study, 1984 (Box 41)
    - JWT image studies, 1984 (Box 41)
    - SRI agency audit and survey, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Research Conference, 1975, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Review Board Procedures, 1972 (Box 41)
    - Selling/Advertising to men--case histories, circa 1980 (Box 41)
  - Skills Inventory Database, 1985-1986 (Box 42)
  - Staffing and job descriptions, 1975 (Box 42)
  - Stress management programs, 1984 (Box 42)
  - Subsidiaries and Divisions
    - General, 1985 (Box 42)
    - Deltakos, 1984-1986 (Box 42)
    - Dialog Division, 1974 (Box 42)
    - Entertainment Group
      - Monthly Manager's Assessment, 1986 (Box 42)
      - USA Symposium, 1985 (Box 42)
    - Hill & Knowlton, 1985-1986 (Box 42)
    - Hispania, 1985-1986 (Box 42)
    - J. Walter Direct, 1985-1986 (Box 42)
    - J. Walter Thompson Direct, 1985 (Box 42)
    - JWT Healthcare Group, 1986 (Box 42)
    - Lord Geller Federico Einstein (LGFE), 1985 (Box 42)
    - Soskin Thompson, 1984-1986 (Box 42)
    - Thompson Recruitment
      - General, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 43)
      - Advertising Manual, 1986 (Box 43)
  - Task force, 1985 (Box 43)
  - Tennis Hall of Fame, 1985 (Box 43)
  - T-Plan, 1975 (Box 43)
  - T-Plan presentation, undated (Box 43)
  - Travel policies, 1985 (Box 43)
  - U.S. retirement benefits memo, 1978 (Box 43)
  - Video storyboards, 1984-1986 (Box 43)
  - Wall Street Journal luncheon, 1986 (Box 43)
  - Write if You Want Work advertising campaign, 1984-1985 (Box 43)
  - Zapping, 1984-1986, (2 folders) (Box 43)
- New Business Files, 1973-1986 and undated, (2 boxes)
  - Acme Markets, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Burger King, 1976 (Box 44)